DIVYA YENDAPALLY

UI UX Designer, Developer, and HCI Engineer



designsbydivya.com



dyendapally@gmail.com



678 975 5990



Atlanta Metropolitan Area



linkedin.com/in/divya-y-78a3a293/



github.com/techsaco

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JS

React JS

Sanity io

Adobe Creative Suite

Figma

Balasamiq

Sketch

InVision

MySQL

Java

D1...1.

Blender Git/GitHub/GitLab

EDUCATION

University of Georgia

Franklin College Arts and Sciences

B.S. Computer Science

Minor in Design

2016 - 2020

AWARDS

ACM-W Conference Grant for

Women in Computing, 2020

Presidential Service Award by

President Obama, 2016

Professional Summary

UI UX Designer and Developer passionate about creating digital platforms to better our community. Experience with prototyping designs using various industry software as well as development of websites and mobile applications using JavaScript and React.

EXPERIENCE

PredaSAR Corporation

UI UX Mission Engineer

February 2021- Current

- Contribute to the success of a multidisciplinary team who devise remote sensing satellite missions and capabilities responsive to customer needs
- Rapidly design, mockup, and assist in prototype development of customer-facing user interfaces for ordering and retrieval of PredaSAR products and services
- Develop, document, and deliver, to stakeholders and selected vendors, UI and UX workflows and human factors requirements based on commercial best practices.
- Assist in the design and development of efficient back-end interface elements to support UI/UX solutions
- Support proposal efforts by creating wireframes, graphical products, and other support creative and written content.
- Develop test procedures to validate UI/UX functionality and workflows.

The University of Georgia

Human Computer Interaction

Researcher Jan 2020 – Jul 2020

- Researched designs of past Eco-feedback technology
- Proposedanew solution for a more sustainable environment (Smart Recycle)
- ${\color{blue} \bullet} \ Presented Paper at HCII (Human Computer Interaction International) \\ conference$
- ReceivedACM-W Conference grant
- Paper published by Springer

Research Development Designer at UGA School of Social

Work Aug 2019 – Jul 2020

- Created an application that educates OB/GYNs to provide trauma informed care to victims of sexual assault
- \bullet Tasks include researching Trauma, Women's Health, and design to make the application most user-centric
- Prototyped, designed, and developed a mobile application
- $\bullet \ Presented T.I.M. E (Trauma Informed Medicine Education) at CURO \\ Symposium$

Chick-Fil-A Corporate Digital Technology

Intern May 2019 – Aug 2019

- Responsible for designing key components for future applications at the Corporate of fice. Specific parts of the company that I got to assist with, are the Chick-Fil-A Wallboards and the CFA NOW applications.
- Implemented a photography extension, which allowed restaurant operators to personalize their iOS wallboard and digital displays
- Created a solution to reduce calls during hours of less operation, depending on the location of the restaurant

TEDxUGA Speaker

November 2019

• Inthis TEDxtalk, I proposed that we could design an application that uses technology to help create virtual therapy sessions, initially under the supervision of atherapist, and eventually on the client's own. We could use technology to help clients gethelp on their schedule, and not on their therapist's schedule. May be, we could one day even use technology to detect when a client may need immediate attention, based on their responses or interactions with their therapist.